### Hendra Kurniawan

hendrakurniawann46@gmail.com | +6287840491199 | https://www.linkedin.com

### **PROFILE**

Hendra Kurniawan, an experienced individual in the manufacturing industry, has a diverse work history. With 3 years of experience working in Japan as a CNC Machinist in a company specializing in the production of mold plates for car components, Hendra then transitioned to a role as a Maintenance Automation Technician at PT Panasonic Industrial Devices Batam, a Semiconductor manifacturing company, where he worked for 2 years. Currently, he is working at PT Sumitomo Wiring Systems Batam Indonesia as a Design Development. While studying at Batam State Politechnic and committed to continue learning and growing in his career.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **Batam State Polytechnic**

Batam, ID

Bachelor Degree, Electronic Engineering Technology

Present

Automation Industri, PCB Design, Internet of Things, Mechanical Design GPA 7 Smester: 3.65

#### RELEVANT COURSEWORK

Automation Engineer, Automation Development, IoT Engineer, Design Manufacture Development, Prototype Modelling, PCB Design.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

**Programming Language**: C++, Python

Software: FluidSIM, CX-Programmer, Machine Expert(Schneider PLC), EasyEda, Visual Basic Studio, IDE, Autodesk Fushion360, Autodesk Inventor, AutoCad, SolidWorks, Ms Office, Ms Excel.

#### **CERTIFIED SKILL**

• PLC (BNSP)

# **EXPERIENCE**

### PT Sumitomo Wiring Systems Batam Indonesia Development Design

Batam, ID

October 2023 - Present

• Head Division

- Lead coordination with Japan Sumitomo Development Department to support the introduction of new products.
- Act as Project Planner for new product trials, from initial design review to final validation.
- Analyze Wire Harness manufacturing processes to improve productivity, ensure quality, and optimize cost.
- PIC of monthly meetings to report product trial progress and next action plans.
- Coordinate with cross-functional departments to ensure trial success and smooth transition to mass production.
- Maintain comprehensive documentation related to trials, process improvements, and engineering evaluations.
- Identify potential risks and implement countermeasures during the trial and development
- Support continuous improvement activities and propose process optimizations for long-term efficiency.

Design Engineer

June 2023 – September 2023

- Performed checking and verification for new product designs (Cable Harness).
- In charge of conducting trials for new products
- Analyzed manufacturing processes to:
  - Improve productivity
  - Control efficiency
  - Ensure product compliance with customer specifications.
- Responsible for organizing and reporting in monthly internal engineering meetings.

# **PT Panasonic Industrial Devices Batam**

Batam, ID June 2021 – June 2023

Maintenance Automation Technician

- **Incharge Line Production**
- Analyze and troubleshoot any abnormalities in products and machine
- Mantaining productivity and line efficiency
- Maintenance

# エムケイケイ株式会社/MKK Co.,LTD

Ama City, JP April 2018 – April 2021

Computer Numerical Control Machinist

- Incharge for 3 CNC Milling Machine & 1 CNC Wirecut
- Setter for tools and product
- Maintenance
- Trainer for Japanese New Employee

### PROJECT EXPERIENCE

### **Smart Door Lock System using Eye Movement Detection**

July 2024 - Dec 2024

Machine Learning (College Project)

Developed a smart door lock system using Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) for authentication through eye movement detection. The system processes eye images, trains a CNN model, and evaluates reliability and responsiveness.

Relocation of 20 Work Points of Sumitomo Wiring System Development Nov 2023 – June 2024 Sumitomo Wiring System Batam Indonesia (Section Project)

As the Head of Division, I led and collaborated with my team in successfully relocating 20 development work points from SWS Design Section Japan (SWS DS) to SWS Batam Indonesia Design Section (SWSBI DS). This strategic transfer was carried out through direct training and knowledge transfer sessions conducted by Japanese engineers, ensuring that the processes, standards, and quality requirements were fully adopted and implemented in the local operation.

### Rent Car Guard Internet of Things (College Project)

Feb 2023 – July 2023

This device improves rental car security with a speed alarm that triggers a buzzer and sends notifications when speed limits are exceeded, GPS tracking to monitor location, and an engine cutoff feature if the car isn't returned within 24 hours, reducing risks of theft, damage, and accidents.